
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>WWII Indoctrination in Okinawa WORKING TITLE</title>
                <author>Gerald E. Thomas</author>
                <editor>Tristan Curd, Megan Reed, Arka Maitra, Izchel Quintero</editor>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<p>Publication Information</p>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>Photographs taken from the Gerald E. Thomas collection in the Archives &amp; Special Collections at the University of Nebraska-Lincoln</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<p>Just off the coast of Japan sits a small island, a little under half the size of
				Rhode Island. This island is host to subtropical climates, excessive humidity, and
				an annual rainfall of approximately 83 inches. Here, with its hilly plateaus, peaks
				that reach upward to 1,650 feet, ravines trekking mazes across the land, and the
				plains with rolling hills, stands Okinawa. </p>
			<p>Though Okinawa is only 300 miles from Japan, their economic and cultural ties were
				more connected to China until the seventeenth century. Between 1871 and 1879 Japan’s
				hold on Okinawa loosened, but in 1879 Okinawa became a prefecture of Japan. </p>
			<p>Okinawans, while they resemble Japanese people, are different culturally and have
				different racial origins. The Okinawans have a mixed racial origin with very little
				European blood; only the Itoman area shows noticeable mixture with Portuguese blood.
				Besides blood lines Okinawans are also seen as mild-mannered, courteous, and
				subservient and are said to have no value in exactness, cleanliness, and
				orderliness. However, looking through history itself, this exact description could
				be applied to any group of conquered people by the conquerors. On this note, it is
				also important to point out that the native language of Okinawa is Luchuan or
				Ryukyuan, however, in large cities like Naha and Shuri, Japanese was widely spoken.
				Following the war in 1945, there is documented evidence of Japanese teachers in
				Okinawan schools teaching in Japanese. This transition helped further the transition
				of Okinawa into Japanese culture. </p>
			<p>An interesting fact to add here is that while most Okinawans consider themselves
				Japanese they do consider themselves Okinawan first. But during the war it was clear
				Japan likely did not feel the same way. While Japan made claims to protect the
				Okinawan people they used Okinawa caves to shelter in while leaving the natives
				above as a barrier between Japan forces and American explosives. It was mentioned in
				The Rape of Okinawa article from Duke University Press, that many if not most
				American soldiers were unaware of the civilan death toll as it was rarely mentioned
				to them. One commander of the Sixth Marine Division left after the three month long
				campaign on the tiny island with the belief only 20,000 civilians had died in the
				fighting. Due to destruction of documents from battles and the cruel treatment by
				Japanese forces it was not immediately known that native Okinawans lost 150,000 of
				their people. </p>
			<p>During the bombing of the southern part of Okinawa Japan forces ordered Okinawan
				natives to the northern part of the island which was lined with “dummie
				fortification” giving the false sense of resistance for U.S. Marine forces and the
				surprise of more than double the number of expected civilians. The U.S. Army forces
				faced more resistance in the south and found fewer than expected civilians. During
				this invasion, U.S. military was instructed to avoid damaging specific native towns,
				unfortunately they leveled many of them instead. The fighting forces continued to
				push for usage of the island to be military based, leaving the natives with very
				little room to live. This became such a problem a Navy captain was quoted saying
				“What do they expect us to do hang them from sky-hooks?” (Ford, Pg 178)</p>
			<p>When the ashes finally settled from the battle, Okinawans were no longer at the mercy
				of Japan but now of the American forces. Six weeks prior to Tokyo surrendering,
				American forces took control of Okinawa with an occupation that would last until
				1972. While Okinawa was left to the combat forces’ control; mainland Japan was left
				to American Civilians to plan the purpose of post war occupation and only lasted
				till 1952. Tokyo even volunteered to “donate” the island of Okinawa to the United
				States. During the war Japan used racial unity to try to convert Okinawans into
				fighters and when this failed used them as fodder, and once the war was over they
				abandoned Okinawans with the mindset of a conqueror giving up their “inferior and
				dispensable” people to save their higher valued mainland. While Japan returned to
				their daily lives and benefited from job and baby booms, Okinawa was left to fend
				for itself with its new foreign conquerors.</p>
			<p>Among those conquerors were social scientists who came with the purpose of
				understanding how to interact and handle conquered people. They were in charge of
				calculating how to relocate and handle the natives. It became very clear to the
				social scientist that Okinawans were self-reliant, resilient, sophisticated, and
				ready to return to normal when given the opportunity. After several months of U.S.
				occupation it was decided to relocate Okinawans throughout the island and reunite
				them with family and communities. When military officials asked Okinawan leaders’
				opinion on how to best approach this they were surprised to learn the Okinawans had
				already compiled a census of where people were and where they were from, along with
				a plan to transport people from town to town without wasting any room in the
				trucks.</p>
			<p>In articles like Occupation Experiences on Okinawa it seems while social scientist
				inhabited Okinawa, the Okinawans experienced some relief but with the departure of
				the scientist in October 1945, natives found themselves left with a military force
				less interested in their behavior and ways as a society and more with their own
				military interest in mind. As acknowledged before the military leveled many towns
				and took land for their bases. Often times they took prime land that would be
				essential in tourism and economic value for Okinawans. Many Okinawans oppose the
				presence of the bases concerned that the military makes their island a prime target
				for attacks by other militaries, that the bases impeded their economic growth, and
				due to the Status of Forces Agreement make it difficult to prosecute perpetrators in
				the military and their dependents for crimes they commit.</p>
		</body>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00011.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>(Approx) 15 May 45. Okinawa. One of the many Japanese dugouts that honeycombed
				the ridges of Okinawa. In addition to use as storage space, they were used as
				resting places for personnel. (Signal Corps Photo). Fusco, 3231 Sig. Photo
				Det.</figDesc>
			<note>The “typhoon of bombs and shells,” as the natives called the American explosives,
				slew and maimed more civilians than the Japanese defenders in the “underground
				battleships” they had made of their caves.” (Feifer, p.33) </note>
		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-0012.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>(Aprox) 7 May 1945. Okinawa. The city of Naha, largest on the island of Okinawa
				(pop 65,000) lies in ruins, the result of heavy and continuous bombings as the U.S.
				tenth army advances southward toward the city against stiff Jap resistance. A Jap
				ship rests on the bottom of the shallow water at lower left, while two large
				buildings, believed to be schools can be seen still standing in upper center and
				right. (Signal Corps Photo). Rosenthal, 3235 Sig. Photo Det.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00013.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Balcony--Looking toward stage Naha opera house. 3223 Sig Photo Det.
				Photographer: Thompson</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00131.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>View of interior of Naha Opera House thru large hole in back wall. 3223 Sig
				Photo Det. Photographer: Thompson</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00131.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Orchestra floor--Looking toward stage--Naha Opera House. 3223 Sig Photo Det.
				Photographer: Thompson</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00133.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>View from Naha Opera House roof showing Naha ruins--Looking West. 3223 Sig
				Photo Det. Photographer: Thompson</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00020.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Balcony--Naha Opera House. 3223 Sig Photo Det. Photographer: Thompson</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00019.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>View from Naha Opera House roof showing Naha ruins--Looking East. 3223 Sig
				Photo Det. Photographer: Thompson</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00129.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>View from Naha Opera House roof showing Naha ruins--Looking Northwest. 3223 Sig
				Photo Det. Photographer: Thompson</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00130.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>View from Naha Opera House roof showing Naha ruins--Looking North. 3223 Sig
				Photo Det. Photographer: Thompson</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00017.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Exterior view of Naha Opera House. 3223 Sig Photo Det. Photographer:
				Thompson</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00016.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>View from Naha Opera House roof showing Naha ruins--looking south. 3223 Sig
				Photo Det. Photographer: Thompson</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00181.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>View from Naha Opera House roof showing Naha ruins--Looking Southeast. 3223 Sig
				Photo Det. Photographer: Thompson</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00015.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Naha, Okinawa. Ruins of Christian church, now occupied by 3295 Quartermaster
				Service Co. (signal Corps Photo). Malashuk, 3925 Sig Photo SV Co.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00049.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Med shot scene on Christian church in Naha on Okinawa now occupied by
				3295 quartermaster serv co US Army. t/3 Alex Malashuk, Sig Photo Det (Signal Corps
				Photo)</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00053.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>(Formerly:10A/POA-158-45-958) Okinawa. Aerial view of Kadena Circle. (Signal
				Corps Photo). Mokis, Photo Det 28, 3117 Sig SV BN</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00044.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. A bailey bridge is constructed over a river on highway 6N, parallel to
				a Jap bridge, to accommodate heavy two way trafic at this point. (Signal corps
				Photo). Pierce, 3234 Sig. Photo Det.</figDesc>
			<note>Many captions mention the slur “Jap” as these were U.S. military photographs. It
				is important to point out while Japanese distance themselves from Okinawans, to
				outsiders like the U.S. they were seen as the same people. </note>
		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00028.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Showing two bridges on river near Machinato. Four weasel have been
				knocked out and abandoned due to heavy enemy mortar fire. (Signal Corps Photo).
				Barabas, 3240 Sig Serv Det)</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00023.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. An aerial view of Naha, Okinawa's chief city, taken from a cub plane
				which is used by the artillery for direction fire and observation. (Signal Corps
				Photo). Rosenthal, 3235 Sig Photo Det.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00039.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Great White Father', 'Boss' Thomas and crew of small Okinawa Gooks. Taken on
				site of demolished Oki residence 25 Apr 45. With a smattering of the Jap language
				&amp; a quantity of pantomime I got a lot of work out of these 'kids'. They are very
				meticulous, friendly, &amp; apparently tireless. (This WDA [?] pose is not
				normal!)</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00043.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa, Ryukyus. A Japanese girl [woman] is held by a member of the 7th Inf.
				Division. Photo by Ditzian, 1st Info. &amp; His.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00064.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. A group of Okinawan Native girls climb into an army truck which will
				take them to the 7th Inf Div Area, where they will work in the QM laundry. (Signal
				Corps Photo). Pinsky, 3223 Sig Photo Det</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00065.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Tokashiki Shima, Kerama Rhetto, Ryukyus. Okinawan child in the arms of 1st Sgt.
				John S. Evans of Springfield, S.C., was rescued by troops of the 77th Infantry
				Division. The Division frustrated an attempted mass suicide of civilians during the
				early stages of the battle. U.S. Army Photo by Roberts, 1st Information &amp;
				Historical Service.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00066.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Many ancient customs are in evidence on Okinawa. These Native women
				return to their homes carrying their clothing atop their heads in primitive fashion
				near the town of Shimobaru. (Signal Corps Photo). Shipherd, 3236 Sig. Photo
				Det.</figDesc>
			<note>In the caption of this photo we can see the difference in the soldiers'
				perspective of native Okinawans and that of the Social Scientist. While Social
				Scientists saw the Okinawans as a sophisticated people, Army soldiers referred to
				them and aspects of their lives as “primitive”. </note>
		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00067.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. A Japanese soldier and woman walk along coral flat along beach on way
				to collection point. (Signal Corps Photo). Hendrickson, Sig Photo Det 27, 3925 Sig
				Photo SV CO</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00071.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa, Ryukyus. An Okinawa old woman, hurt while running, is given first aid
				by men of the 6th Inf. Div. On right is PFC. J.P. Conley of Saliersville, KY., who
				is trying to make the Natives understand that the camera won't hurt them. Photo by
				Gurtcheff-3117 Sig. Serv. BN.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00072.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Children in a class room at Takasu School which is under the
				supervision of AMG Officers. (Signal Corps Photo). McGill, 3241 Sig Photo
				Det</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00075.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Many Okinawan Natives are evacuated from caves and shelters where they
				were hiding during the battle across Okinawa all Jap soldiers who refused to
				surrender were killed and the Natives were taken to places of safety by the 106 and
				105 Regts of the 27th Inf Div (U.S. Army Photo). Gurtcheff, 1st Info &amp; Hist
				Serv</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00076.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Zamami Shima, Kerama Rhetto, Ryukyus. First native civilians (Okinawa) return
				to Zamami town after American occupation. Civilians were herded into municipal
				building as they returned from their hillside caves, and kept there until the
				following day when military government officials came ashore to take charge of the
				situation. U.S. Army Photo by Faircloth, 1st Information &amp; Historical
				Service</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00077.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Male civilians of soldier age who surrendered to the 105th Regt, 27th
				Ine. Div. line up for identification tags. (Signal Corps Photo). Belgin, 3240 Sig.
				Photo Det.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00079.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. A Japanese 1st Lt., who was with a machine gun company, is married to
				his sweetheart, a 19 year old Okinawan who served as a volunteer nurse with the
				Japs. The Lieutenant surrendered to save the life of the girl, and the marriage
				ceremony was performed by an army chaplain. To the rear of the bride stands the
				bridesmaid, an English speaking Hawaiian who has a brother fighting in Italy with
				the Hawaiian troops. (Signal Corps Photo). Photographer Unknown</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00080.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. XXIV Corps Headquarters. An American civil wedding ceremony is
				conducted by an army chaplain for Japanese prisoners found in a dave just behind the
				front lines. The Jap bridegroom was a 1st Lt with a machine gun company, and the
				Okinawan bride a volunteer nurse with the Jap forces. The bridesmaid (to the rear of
				the bride) is an English speaking Hawaiian. A GI plays the wedding music as others
				look on. (Signal Corps Photo). Photographer Unknown</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00086.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. T/3 Nobuo D. Kischiue, of Hanford, Calif., A Nesei interpreter of the
				27th Inf. Div. interrogates Okinawan evacuees from Shure, in a village north of
				Nago, in an effort to obtain information about the defense set up in Shure, the
				heart of the Jap defense system in the bitterly contested lower half of Okinawa.
				(signal Corps Photo). Miller, 3240 Sig. Photo Det.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00087.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Japanese women and girls return from the fields with their baskets,
				laden with sweet potates [sic], atop their heads and cross a brook; (they didn't
				drop a potatoe.) (Signal Corps Photo). Adams, 3234 Sig. Photo Det.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00088.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Native women harvest potatoes on Okinawa with the aid of crude hoes.
				The baskets full of potatoes in the foreground testify to the success of their crop.
				(Signal Corps Photo). Adams, 3234 Sig Photo Det.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00095.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Higa, Kamado, age 63, Okinawan snake catcher from Nakao displaying the
				deadly snake Habu found in Okinawa. In catching a snake he uses a hollow piece of
				bamboo with a heavy piece of wire with a curve on the end which runs through the
				center of bamboo. He has been catching these snakes for 20 yrs and was paid 20 yen
				for each snake by the Jap govt. The Habu snake is sometimes as long as 7ft. S Sgt
				Mokis, Photo Asgmt Det 28 (Signal Corps Photo).</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00096.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Higa, Kamado, age 63, Okinawan snake catcher from Nakao, demonstrating
				to Mil Govt personnel how to handle a Habu to open up its jaw. S Sgt Mokis, Photo
				Asgmt Det 28 (Signal Corps Photo)</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00097.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Ada, Okinawa. In order to carry rations and supplies to men of the 27th Div
				mopping-up in the mountains of northern Okinawa, the 105th Inf Regt, under the
				command of Col Walter S Winn, formed two companies composed of Native Okinawans
				supplied and paid by the military government. Here two cooks from "J" Co, which is
				made up of 66 Natives, prepare a soup of sweet potato leaves and vines which will be
				carried to the front line troops. (Signal Corps Photo). Mokis, 3925 Sig Photo SV
				CO</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00098.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Maj Harold E Keller, Topeka, Kansas, addresses the assembly at the
				opening of the Koza school system. (Signal Corps Photo). McGill, 3241 Sig Photo
				Det</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00099.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Students studying school lessons. (Signal Corps Photo). McGill, 3241
				Sig Photo Det)</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00100.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. School children playing tug of war during physical training period at
				Takesu. (Signal Corps Photo). McGill, 3241 Sig Photo Det</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00102.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Two Okinawan women in the town of Shimabaku, war having passed beyond
				them, pound rice in front of their homes while the rest of the family watches.
				(signal Corps Photo). Fusco, 3231 Sig. Serv. Det.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00103.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Miss Cheeko Shingari, a Native schoolteacher, is conducting a class
				out of doors. The school is located in the town of Shimbaku, and is supervised by
				our military authorities. (Signal Corps Photo). Fusco, 3231 Sig Serv Det</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00104.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Miss Cheeko Shingari, a Native schoolteacher, is shown at her
				blackboard. Classes are held out of doors, and are being conducted under the
				supervision of military authorities. (Signal Corps Photo). Fusco, 3231 Sig SV
				Det</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00106.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. A typical street scene in the town of Shimobaru, with the civilians
				pursuing their routine activities. (Signal Corps Photo). Shipherd, 3236 Sig Photo
				Det</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00108.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. 10th Army MP guards Okinawan children working in the fields. (Signal
				Corps Photo). Pierce, 3234 Sig. Photo Det.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00110.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Jap prisoners of war stand in front of the graves of General Isama
				Cho, Chief of Staff, and Lt Gen Mitsuro Ushijima, former commanding General of the
				32d Imperial Japanese Army, on Hill 98. Picture made at request of the Office of
				Psychological Warfare. (Signal Corps Photo). 3233D Sig Photo Det, Photog
				Unknown</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00107.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. A Jap prisoner of war kneels in front of the graves of general Isama
				Cho, chief of staff, and Lt Gen Mitsuro Ushijima, former commanding general of the
				32nd Imperial Japanese Army, on Hill 98. Picture made at request of the Office of
				Psychological Warfare. (Signal Corps Photo) 3233 Sig Photo Det - Photog
				Unknown</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00112.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Many of the adult male civilians of soldier age who surrendered to the
				105th Regt, 27th Inf. Div., are appointed to various duties. This former barber, at
				a military government orphanage, applies his tonsorial skill to one of the orphans.
				(Signal Corps Photo). Belgin, 3240 Sig. Photo Det.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00113.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Many customs of the far East are in evidence on Okinawa. A seven year
				old girl is shown carrying a two month old baby on her back in ancient fashion in
				the village of Nodake. (signal Corps Photo). Adams, 3234 Sig. Photo Det.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00114.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Native women are honored by having Americans in to tea. L-R: Capt. L.
				T. Tolman and Capt. Chancey M. Depuy, with their shoes off, make themselves at home.
				(Signal Corps Photo). Adams, 3234 Sig. Photo Det.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00115.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Capt Jeanette Butler, Waterloo, N.Y., Senior Nurse at the 69th Field
				Hospital, talks to Native mother and child. (Signal Corps Photo). Pinsky, 3223 Sig
				Photo Det</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00116.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. General view of Military Government Center at Isikawa, showing
				temporary shelters for civilians. (Signal Corps Photo). Munn, photo Det 28, 3925 Sig
				Photo SV CO</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00117.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Male civilians are well saturated with DDT, lice powder, by PFC. M. C.
				Manley of Chicago, ILL., after their belongings and person have been carefully
				searched the civilians surrendered to the 105th Regt, 27th Inf. Div. and were
				brought to Tiara for interrogation. (Signal Corps Photo). Belgin, 3240 Sig. Photo
				Det.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00118.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. PVT Paul Peevy, Gainsville, GA., talks to Tomeko, a young Native girl
				who works in the BN Officers' Mess. (Signal corps Photo). Barabas, 3240 Sig Photo
				Det</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00119.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. PW's are questioned during processing. (Signal Corps Photo). Pierce,
				3234 Sig Photo Det</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00120.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Okinawan civilians trudge along a road to the area designated by the
				Military government. Many carry their possessions in the traditional manner atop
				their heads. (signal Corps Photo). Photog. Unknown, 3233 Sig. Photo Det.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00123.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Atop tower marker on hill looking towards Shuri. T/R Kenneth Adams,
				3234 Sig Photo Det (Signal Corps Photo)</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00138.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Retreating enemy troops on Okinawa left much equipment in caves which
				were hurriedly vacated. This soldier, advancing on a cave but recently occupied by
				Japs, surveys such a scene. (Signal Corps Photo). Adams, 3234 Sig Photo
				Det</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00140.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Marines viewing Jap temple. T/4 Kenneth Adams, 3234 Sig Photo Det
				(Signal Corps Photo)</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00147.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Smoke and flame mark the battle-front in southern sector on Okinawa as
				XXIV Corps pushes ahead against stiff Jap opposition. Two tanks can be seen here
				(left foreground), one in the act of burning out a Jap strongpoint with its deadly
				flame-thrower (Signal Corps Photo). Rosenthal, 3235 Sig Photo Det</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00182.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. This Geisha girl is doing a dance done for travelers going from
				Okinawa to the Mainland of Japan at a festival, Taira, Okinawa. Geisha girls
				entertained service personnel and navtives [sic] at the fete. They were formerly
				inmates of Geisha houses on the island. (Signal Corps Photo). Photog.
				Unknown.</figDesc>
			<note>It was noted that performance arts were very important to the Okinawa people and
				cities like Naha had opera houses to house these performances.</note>
		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00183.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Taira, Okinawa. Troops and Natives watch dance being performed by Geisha girls
				who formerly worked in the Okinawa Geisha Houses. (Signal Corps Photo). Munn
				Detphoto Det 28, 3925 Sig Photo SV Co</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00184.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Taira, Okinawa. Two Geisha girls, who formerly worked in the Okinawa Geisha
				Houses, perform a typical dance for American troops. (Signal Corps Photo). Munn,
				Photo Det 28, 3925 Sig Photo SV CO</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00185.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Geisha girls shown doing the sword dance of soldiers during the dance
				festival held for American troops stationed at Taira, Okinawa. (Signal Corps Photo).
				Munn, Photo Det 28, 3925 Sig Photo SV CO</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00186.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Geisha girls make up backstage for their dances in the traditional
				fashion at Taira, Okinawa. A native dance festival was held, attended by the U.S.
				tenth Army, Marine and Navy personnel. The dances originated in the ancient days
				when the island was ruled by a king, and interpreted by the girls who formerly
				entertained at Geisha Houses. (Signal Corps Photo). Photog. Unknown.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00187.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Geisha girls at Taira, Okinawa entertain service and native audience
				with a dance portraying some moments in the life os a fisherman and his wife. The
				The [sic] festival was devoted to the native dances of Okinawa as interpreted by the
				girls, former inmates of Geisha Houses on the island. (Signal Corps Photo). Phog.
				Unknown.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00200.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Geisha girls, performing for American troops stationed at Taira,
				Okinawa, do the Dance to Girl and Lover during the dance festival held at Taira.
				(Signal Corps Photo). Munn, Photo Det 28, 3925 Sig Photo SV CO</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00201.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Geisha girls in the finale "Chorus Line" during the dance festival
				held for American troops stationed at Taira, Okinawa. (Signal Corps Photo). Munn,
				Photo Det 28, 3925 Sig Photo SV CO</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00202.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. These Geisha girls are interpreting a dance done for travelers going
				from Okinawa to the mainland of Japan at a festival. The girls, former inmates of
				Geisha houses on the island, entertained the service and native audience with their
				dances. (Signal Corps Photo). Photog. Unknown.</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00223.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Prisoner of war in Iscom Stockade gets a hari cut before evacuation to Hawaii.
				(Signal Corps Photo). Cochran, 3234 Sig Photo Det</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00238.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Native Okinawans packing food and supplies to men of the 165th Inf Regt, 27th
				Div, fighting on Kushi Take Mountain. (Signal Corps Photo). Munn, Photo Det 28, 3117
				Sig SV BN</figDesc>

		</figure>
		<figure>
			<graphic url="0116-00008.jpg"/>
			<figDesc>Okinawa. Jap searchlight in cave just north of Naha Airfield. Pierce, 3234 Sig
				Photo Det (Signal Corps Photo)</figDesc>

		</figure>

	</text>
</TEI>
