<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Title</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div>
      	<head> Military</head>
      	<figure>
      		<graphic url="images/0116-00043.jpg"/>
      		<figDesc>Okinawa, Ryukyus. A Japanese girl [woman] is held by a member of the 7th
      			Inf. Division. Photo by Ditzian, 1st Info. &amp; His.</figDesc>
      		
      	</figure>
      	<figure>
      		<graphic url="images/0116-00065.jpg"/>
      		<figDesc>Tokashiki Shima, Kerama Rhetto, Ryukyus. Okinawan child in the arms of 1st
      			Sgt. John S. Evans of Springfield, S.C., was rescued by troops of the 77th
      			Infantry Division. The Division frustrated an attempted mass suicide of
      			civilians during the early stages of the battle. U.S. Army Photo by Roberts, 1st
      			Information &amp; Historical Service.</figDesc>
      		
      	</figure>
      	<figure>
      		<graphic url="images/0116-00071.jpg"/>
      		<figDesc>Okinawa, Ryukyus. An Okinawa old woman, hurt while running, is given first
      			aid by men of the 6th Inf. Div. On right is PFC. J.P. Conley of Saliersville,
      			KY., who is trying to make the Natives understand that the camera won't hurt
      			them. Photo by Gurtcheff-3117 Sig. Serv. BN.</figDesc>
      		
      	</figure>
      	<figure>
      		<graphic url="images/0116-00080.jpg"/>
      		<figDesc>Okinawa. XXIV Corps Headquarters. An American civil wedding ceremony is
      			conducted by an army chaplain for Japanese prisoners found in a dave just behind
      			the front lines. The Jap bridegroom was a 1st Lt with a machine gun company, and
      			the Okinawan bride a volunteer nurse with the Jap forces. The bridesmaid (to the
      			rear of the bride) is an English speaking Hawaiian. A GI plays the wedding music
      			as others look on. (Signal Corps Photo). Photographer Unknown</figDesc>
      		
      	</figure>
      	<figure>
      		<graphic url="images/0116-00097.jpg"/>
      		<figDesc>Ada, Okinawa. In order to carry rations and supplies to men of the 27th Div
      			mopping-up in the mountains of northern Okinawa, the 105th Inf Regt, under the
      			command of Col Walter S Winn, formed two companies composed of Native Okinawans
      			supplied and paid by the military government. Here two cooks from "J" Co, which
      			is made up of 66 Natives, prepare a soup of sweet potato leaves and vines which
      			will be carried to the front line troops. (Signal Corps Photo). Mokis, 3925 Sig
      			Photo SV CO</figDesc>
      		
      	</figure>
      	<figure>
      		<graphic url="images/0116-00110.jpg"/>
      		<figDesc>Okinawa. Jap prisoners of war stand in front of the graves of General Isama
      			Cho, Chief of Staff, and Lt Gen Mitsuro Ushijima, former commanding General of
      			the 32d Imperial Japanese Army, on Hill 98. Picture made at request of the
      			Office of Psychological Warfare. (Signal Corps Photo). 3233D Sig Photo Det,
      			Photog Unknown</figDesc>
      		
      	</figure>
      	<figure>
      		<graphic url="images/0116-00107.jpg"/>
      		<figDesc>Okinawa. A Jap prisoner of war kneels in front of the graves of general
      			Isama Cho, chief of staff, and Lt Gen Mitsuro Ushijima, former commanding
      			general of the 32nd Imperial Japanese Army, on Hill 98. Picture made at request
      			of the Office of Psychological Warfare. (Signal Corps Photo) 3233 Sig Photo Det
      			- Photog Unknown</figDesc>
      		
      	</figure>
      	<figure>
      		<graphic url="images/0116-00117.jpg"/>
      		<figDesc>Okinawa. Male civilians are well saturated with DDT, lice powder, by PFC.
      			M. C. Manley of Chicago, ILL., after their belongings and person have been
      			carefully searched the civilians surrendered to the 105th Regt, 27th Inf. Div.
      			and were brought to Tiara for interrogation. (Signal Corps Photo). Belgin, 3240
      			Sig. Photo Det.</figDesc>
      		
      	</figure>
      	<figure>
      		<graphic url="images/0116-00119.jpg"/>
      		<figDesc>Okinawa. PW's are questioned during processing. (Signal Corps Photo).
      			Pierce, 3234 Sig Photo Det</figDesc>
      		
      	</figure>
      	<figure>
      		<graphic url="images/0116-00138.jpg"/>
      		<figDesc>Okinawa. Retreating enemy troops on Okinawa left much equipment in caves
      			which were hurriedly vacated. This soldier, advancing on a cave but recently
      			occupied by Japs, surveys such a scene. (Signal Corps Photo). Adams, 3234 Sig
      			Photo Det</figDesc>
      		
      	</figure>
      	<figure>
      		<graphic url="images/0116-00223.jpg"/>
      		<figDesc>Prisoner of war in Iscom Stockade gets a hari cut before evacuation to
      			Hawaii. (Signal Corps Photo). Cochran, 3234 Sig Photo Det</figDesc>
      		
      	</figure>
         </div>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
